Newland/Zeuner Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Instrumental Music (Box 5-23, Box 56-57)
  - Music for solo instruments (Box 5-20, Box 57)
    - Piano, 2 hands: Transcriptions - Printed music (Box 11-12)
      - By Composer (Box 11-12)
        - Bellini, Vincenzo
          - Ouverturen für das Pianoforte. No. 13. Bellini, z. Oper: Die Puritaner. Braunschweig: G. M. Meyer, Jr., n.d., Pl. no. 383. (Box 11)
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 7,8,11,62] Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Includes: Nro. 7 - Der Pirat. Pl. no. (503). Nro. 8 - Montecchi e Capuleti. (Romeo und Julie) Pl. no. (476). Nro. 11 - La Straniera. Pl. no. (479). Nro. 62 - Bianca e Fernando. Pl. no. (520). (Box 11)
        - Cramer, Johann Baptist (arranger)
          - Lord MacDonald's Reel, Arranged as a Rondo for the Piano-Forte by J.B. Cramer [London]: Muzio Clementi and Co., n.d., Pl. no. 477. (Box 11)
        - Della Maria, Pierre-Antoine-Dominique
          - L'Opera comique. [Potpourri]., Pl. no. 20. (Box 11)
          - Ouverture Du Prisonnier ou La Ressemblance. Musique du Cn. Dellamaria arrangée pour le Piano par L'Auteur Paris: Janet, [1798]., Pl. no. C. (Box 11)
        - Donizetti, Gaetano
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 45,47,48,49,63,64] Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Includes: Nro. 45 - Anna Bolena. Pl. no. (503). Nro. 47 - Der Liebestrank. Pl. no. (505). Nro. 48 - Lucia di Lammermoor. Pl. no. (506). Nro. 49 - Lucrezia Borgia. Pl. no. (507). Nro. 63 - Fausta. Pl. no. (521). Nro. 64 - Gemma di Vergi. Pl. no. (522). (Box 11)
        - Gluck, Christoph Willibald
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 50,51] Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Includes: Nro. 50 - Alceste. Pl. no. (508). Nro. 51 - Armida. Pl. no. (509). (Box 11)
        - Hérold, Louis Joseph Ferdinand
          - Overture to Zampa by Herold., Signed W. A. Newland; Pl. no. 5754. (Box 11)
        - Kelly, Michael
          - The Overture to the Opera of Blue Beard as Performed at the Theatre Royal Drury Lane. Arranged for the Piano Forte by J. F. Bohlius. London: E. Riley, n.d. (Box 11)
        - Kreutzer, Conradin
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. Nro. 53 - Das Nachtlager von Granada von Conr. Kreutzer. Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Pl. no. (511). (Box 11)
        - Martin y Soler, Vicente
          - Overtura per il Clavicembalo dell'Opera Una Cosa rara Del Sig. V. Martin. Vienna: Artaria Copl., [1787]., Pl. no. 106. (Box 11)
        - Méhul, Etienne-Nicholas
          - Ouverturen für das Pianoforte. Nro. 33 - Méhul, z. Opera: Joseph. Braunschweig: G.M. Meyer, Jr., n.d., Pl. no. 409. (Box 11)
        - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
          - Douze pièces de l'opéra: Figaro de Mozart, arrangées pour le Piano-Forté avec Violon ad libitum. Offenbach s/Mein: Jean André, n.d., Pl. no. 1672 (Box 12)
          - Cosi fan Tutte - Ouverture. Arrangée pour Clavecin ou Pianoforte. Paris: Imbault, n.d., Pl. O. #. 196. (Box 12)
          - Ouverture du Giovani. Arrangée pour le Clavecin ou Pianoforte Composé par Mr. Mozart. Frankfort Sur le Mein: W. N. Haueisen, n.d. (Box 12)
          - Ouverture aus Titus., Pl. no. 121. (Box 12)
          - Ouverture fürs Piano Forte aus der Zauberflöte von W. A. Mozart. Carlsruhe: I. Velten, n.d. (Box 12)
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forté solo. [Nro. 17,18,20,21,22] Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Includes: Nro. 17 - Cosi fan Tutte. Pl. no. (485) Nro. 18 - Entführung. Pl. no. (486). Nro. 20 - Idomeneo. Pl. no. (488). Nro. 21 - Schauspieldirector. Pl. no. (489). Nro. 22 - Titus. Pl. no. (490). (Box 12)
        - Päer, Ferdinando
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forté [Nro. 57,58] Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Includes: Nro. 57 - Sargino. Pl. no. (515). Nro. 58 - Sophonisbe. Pl. no. (516). (Box 12)
        - Reeve, William
          - Overture to the Cabinet, as performed at the Theatre Royal Covent Garden composed by W. Reeve. London: J. Dale, [1802?]. (Box 12)
        - Rifaut, V. (arranger)
          - Ouverture de L'Ambassadrice arrangée par V. Rifaut. (Box 12)
        - Rossini, Gioacchino
          - Ouverture de l'Opera: Armida arrangée pour le Piano-Forte musique de J. Rossini. Bonn: N. Simrock, n.d., Pl. no. 1978. (Box 12)
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. Nro. 59 -Elisabeth von G. Rossini. Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Pl. no. (517). (Box 12)
        - Spontini, Gaspare (Luigi Pacifico)
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 27,28,61] Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Includes: 7 - Cortez. Pl. no. (495). 8 - Vestalin. Pl. no. (496). 1 - Olympia. Pl. no. (516). (Box 12)
        - Weber, Karl Maria Friedrich Ernst (Freiherr von)
          - Ouverture zur grossen romantischen Oper: Euryanthe, für das Pianoforte von C. M. Weber. Erfurt: J. Suppus, n.d. (Box 12)
          - Ouverture to Euryanthe von C. M. von Weber., Title page and last page in W.A. Newland's hand (Box 12)
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 29,30,31,35,36] Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Includes: Nro. 29 - Sylvana. Pl. no. (390). Nro. 30 - Turandot. Pl. no. (391). Nro. 31 - Preciosa. Pl. no. (392). Nro. 35 - Peter Schmoll. Pl. no. (396). Nro. 36 - Abu Hassan. Pl. no. (397). (Box 12)
      - Title only (Box 12)
        - Agamemnon, Ballet pour le Clavecin. Mayence: B. Schott, n.d. (Box 12)
        - Blumen aus 100 Opern eine Ausgewählte Sammlung gefälliger und beliebter Opern Melodien im leichtesten auszuge für's Piano-Forte. Zur Unterhaltung und Aufmunterung für junge Piano-Forte-Spieler zweckmässig eingerichtet von G. W. Marks. Hamburg: Aug. Cranz, n.d., Title page only (Box 12)
        - La Cachucha - The Celebrated Castanet Spanish Dance, as Danced by Melle Fanny Elssler. Arranged for the Piano Forte. Philadelphia: A. Fiot, n.d. (Box 12)
    - Piano, 2 hands: Transcriptions - Manuscripts (Box 12, Box 57)
      - Franzl, Ferdinand
        - Adolph and Clara op. 18 - Overture, also includes: Overture to Vestales by Weigl (Box 12)
      - Nicolai, Ottous
        - Il Templario - Sinfonia (Box 12)
      - Weber, Carl Maria von
        - Der Freischütz - Hunting Chorus (Box 12)
      - Weigl, Joseph
        - Vestales - Overture (Box 57)
    - Piano, 4 or more hands - Printed music (Box 12-13)
      - By Composer (Box 12-13)
        - Brachthuizer, D.
          - Sonate facile à Quatre Mains pour le Pianoforte par D. Brachthuizer. Berlin: J. J. Hummel, n.d. (Box 12)
        - Czerny, Carl
          - Practische Takt-Schule. 44 leichte Uebungsstücke für das Pianoforte zu 4 Händen in fortschreitender Ordnung für Anfänger und vorgerückte Schüler von Carl Czerny 824stes Werk. Heft 2. Offenbach a/M: Johann André, [18-]., Pl. no. 7217. (Box 12)
          - Les Trois Soeurs. Rondinos pour le Piano à 6 mains. Op. 609, No. 5 - Air Suisse par Ch. Czerny. Bonn: N. Simrock, n.d., Pl. no. 3893. (Box 12)
        - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
          - Grande Sonate à quatre mains sur un clavecin ou pianoforte par W. A. Mozart. Oeuvre 12. [K 497] Vienne: Artaria Compl., [1796?]., Pl. no. 108. (Box 12)
        - Onslow, André Georges Louis
          - Grande Duo à Quatre Mains pour le Piano-Forté, par Georges Onslow. Op. 7. Paris: J. Pleyel, n.d., Pl. no. 1004. (Box 13)
        - Pleyel, Ignaz
          - Trois Sonates à quatre mains [pour] le Piano-Forte par [J.] Pleyel. [Offenbach] sur le Mein: J. André, [1789?]., Pl. no. 300.; Title page damaged (Box 13)
        - Ries, Ferdinand
          - Polonaise à Quatre mains pour le Pianoforte par Ferd. Ries. Op. 93. 2me. Bonn: N. Simrock, [182-]., Pl. no. 1984. (Box 13)
      - Title only (Box 13)
        - Primo, Additional miscellaneous pages; Pl. No. 1544 and 4506. (Box 13)
    - Piano, 4 or more hands - Manuscripts (Box 13)
      - Kluge (arranger)
        - Des Walses et Eccoisaises Favorite (Box 13)
      - Riebel
        - Des Marches et des Walses (Box 13)
      - Wanhal, Johann Baptist
        - Petites Pièces (Box 13)
        - [Unidentified], Sonata(?) (Box 13)
    - Piano, 4 or more hands: Transcriptions - Printed music (Box 13-14)
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van
        - Polonoise Concertante à quatre mains pour le Pianoforte par Louis van Beethoven. Tiré de l'Oeuvre 56. Leipzig: A. Kühnel, [180-]., Pl. no. 634. (Box 13)
      - Mayseder, Joseph
        - Duo pour le Pianoforte à 4 mains par Joseph Mayseder. Arrangé d'après le premier Trio pour le Pianoforte, Violon et Violoncelle par Charles Czerny. Oeuvre 34. Vienne: S. A. Steiner, n.d., Pl. no. S:u:C: 3972. (Box 13)
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix
        - Shakespeare's Sommernachtstraum componirt und für das Pianoforte zu vier Händen arrangirt von Felix Mendelssohn Bartholdy. Op. 61, Notturno. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, [18--?]., Pl. no. 7040. (Box 13)
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
        - Ouverture de l'Opera: La Clemenza di Tito par W. A. Mozart arrangée à quatre mains pour Piano-Forte. Mayence: B. Schott, n.d. (Box 13)
        - Ouvertures de W. A. Mozart arrangées à quatre mains pour Piano-Forté par A. Andre. [No. 2,5,8] Offenbach s/M[ein]: J. André, [18-]., Includes: No. 2 - Idomeneo. Pl. no. 3775. No. 5 - Don Juan. Pl. no. 3734. No. 8 - Die Zauberflöte. Pl. no. 3735. (Box 13)
        - Ouvertures pour Piano-Forté à quatre mains. No. 14 - Mozart, der Schauspieldirector. Offenbach s/M: Jean André, n.d., Pl. no. 3837. (Box 13)
        - Sinfonie de W.A. Mozart. [No. 5 in D] arrngée Pour le Pianoforte à quatre mains. Leipsic: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Pl. no. 1904. (Box 13)
        - W. A. Mozart's fünfzehn ausgewählte Sinfonien für das Pianoforte zu vier Händen arrangirt von F. W. Markull. [Nos. 1, 3-8, 11-13] Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Includes: No. 1 - Sinfonie Op. 87 in Ddur (ohne Menuet.) Pl. no. (551). No. 3 - Sinfonie Op. 58 in Esdur. Pl. no. (553). No. 4 - (Jupiter-) Sinfonie Op. 34 in Cdur. Pl. no. (554). No. 5 - Sinfonie in Ddur. Pl. no. (555). No. 6 - Sinfonie in Cdur. Pl. no. (556). No. 7 - Sinfonie in Ddur. Pl. no. (557). No. 8 - Sinfonie in Ddur. Pl. no. (558). No. 11 - Sinfonie in Bdur. Pl. no. (561). No. 12 - Sinfonie in Gdur. Pl. no. (562). No. 13 - Sinfonie in Gmoll. Pl. no. (563). (Box 14)
      - Päer, Ferdinando
        - Overture aus der Oper Sophonisbe zu vier Händen für das Piano-Forte eingerichtet Music von F. Pär. Frankfurt a/M: A. Fischer, n.d., Pl. no. 887.; Publisher information stamped over (Box 14)
    - Piano, 4 hands: Transcriptions - Manuscripts (Box 14)
      - Boieldieu, Adrien (arranger)
        - Caliphe v[on] Bagdad - Ouverture (Box 14)
    - Strings - Printed music (Box 14-16)
      - By Composer (Box 14-16)
        - Beethoven, Ludwig van
          - Sonata per il Piano-forte ed un Violino obligato, scritta in uno stile molto concertante, quasi come d'un concerto. Composta per L. van Beethoven. Opera 47. [Kreutzer] Bonn: N. Simrock, [1805]., Pl. no. 422.; signed M. Müller (Box 14)
          - Sonate pour le Forte-Piano avec un Cor, oû Violoncelle composée par Louis van Beethoven. Oeuvre 17. Vienne: T. Mollo et Comp., [1801]., Pl. no. 147. (Box 14)
          - Sonate für Piano-Forte und Violin von Ludwig van Beethoven. 96tes Werk. Wien: S. A. Steiner und Comp., [1816]., Pl. no. S. et C. 2581. (Box 14)
          - Tre Sonate per il Clavicembalo o Forte-Piano con un Violino dal Sigr. Luigi van Beethoven. Opera 12. Vienna: Artaria e Comp., [1799]., Pl. no. 793.; signed M. Müller (Box 14)
          - Trois Sonates pour Piano-Forté, accompagné de Violon, par L. van Beethoven. Oeuvre 12. Offenbach s/M: J. André, n.d., Pl. no. 2975. (Box 14)
        - Bellini, Vincenzo
          - Potpourri [from] Norma. Arrangée pour deux violons par J. G. Busch. Nouvelle ed. Offenbach s. M.: Jean André, n.d., violino primo; (Apollo. Ouvertures et opéra favoris. No. 32); Pl. no. 6204. (Box 15)
        - Beriot, Charles Auguste de and Julius Benedict
          - Duo Brillant pour Piano et Violon sur les Motifs de l'Opéra de Bellini, La Somnambule par J. Benedict et C. de Beriot. Mayence: B. Schott, n.d., Pl. no. 4388. (Box 15)
        - Beriot, Charles Auguste de and George Alexander Osborne
          - Duo Brillant sur Le Domino Noir par C. de Bériot avec Osborne. Op. 31., Pl. no. T. 903. (Box 15)
          - Duo Brillant pour Piano et Violon sur l'Opéra de Bellini I Puritani par G. A. Osborne et C. de Beriot. Mayence: B. Schott, n.d., Pl. no. 4403. (Box 15)
          - Variations de Concert pour Piano et Violon sur un motif de l'opéra L'Ambassadrice par G. A. Osborne & C. de Beriot. Mayence: B. Schott, n.d., Pl. no. 4868. (Box 15)
        - Beriot, Charles Auguste de and Edward Wolff
          - Grand Duo sur des motifs de Robert le Diable. [Paris]: Maurice Schlesinger, n.d., Pl. no. M.S.3097. (Box 15)
        - Bianchi, Francesco
          - Ouverture Della Villanella Rapita arrangée pour le Clavecin ou Piano Forté par Mr. Haussman. Paris: Le Duc 9me. Année No. 2, n.d. (Box 15)
        - Cambini, Giuseppe Maria
          - Trois Grands Duos extraits des Ouvrages de Pleyel arrangés pour deux Violons par Cambini. Livre 1 & 2. Offenbach s/M: Jean André, n.d., Pl. no. 847, 848. (Box 15)
        - Corelli, Arcangelo
          - Sonate a Violino e Violono o Cimbalo da Arcangelo Corelle da Fusignano Opera Quinta Parte Prima. London: Benjamin Cooke, n.d. (Box 15)
        - Franzl, Ferdinand
          - Concerto pour deux violons par Ferdinand Franzl. Oeuvre 4me. Offenbach sur le Mein: J. André, n.d., violino primo only; Pl. no. 2177. (Box 15)
        - Grétry, André Ernest Modeste
          - Ouverture et quatre Airs de Danse de Panurge de Gretry. Arrangés pour Clavecin ou Forte-Piano avec Accompagnement de Violon par Hulmandel. No. 573. Paris: Mercier, n.d., Pl. no. 6. (Box 15)
        - Herz, Henri and Charles-Philippe Lafont
          - Dernier Grand Duo par H. Herz et Lafont. Op. 110., Pl. no. T. 904. (Box 15)
        - Hünten, Franz
          - Duo Concertant pour Piano & Violin, composé par François Hünten. Oeuvre 23. Paris: A. Farrenc, n.d., Pl. no. A.F. 105. (Box 15)
        - Jaspers, G.
          - Sonatine pour le Clavecin ou Piano Forte Accompagnée d'un Violon par G. Jaspers. Oeuvre III. Berlin: J. J. Hummel, [179-]., Pl. no. 977. (Box 15)
        - Kreutzer, Rodolphe
          - 40 Etudes ou Caprices pour le Violon par R. Kreutzer. Leipsic: Breitkopf & Härtel, [180-]., Pl. no. 373. (Box 15)
        - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
          - Trois Sonates pour le Forte-Piano accompagnés d'un Violon composés par W. A. Mozart. Collection complette Nro. 10. Bronsvic: Magasin de Musique sur la Höhe, n.d., Pl. no. 252. (Box 16)
        - Nucci, J. de
          - Etude en cent variations sur l'accord de FetB pour Violon accompagné d'un second Violon par J. de Nucci. Offenbach s/M: Jean André, n.d., Pl. no. 2210. (Box 16)
        - Pleyel, Ignaz
          - Six Duos faciles et progressifs pour Violon et Viola par I. Pleyel. Oeuvr. 48me. Hambourg: Jean Aug. Böhme, n.d., violino primo (Box 16)
        - Praeger, H. A. (arranger)
          - Recollections of Ireland and Scotland arranged for Violin & Piano Forte by H. A. Praeger. No. 1 - The Moreen in G. Boston: G. P. Reed & Co., n.d., title page only (Box 16)
        - Rode, Pierre
          - Rhode's Celebrated Air with Variations, for the Violin. London: G. Brown, n.d. (Box 16)
        - Ross, John H.
          - Highland Fling see: Ladies Hornpipe, Box 16
        - Rossini, Gioacchino
          - Choix de Douze Ouvertures de la composition de Rossini. No. 8 - L'Otello. Arrangées pour le Forte Piano avec accompagnement de Violon ad libitum. Paris: V.or Dufaut et Dubois, n.d., Pl. no. 8 (Box 16)
        - Schloesser, L.
          - Variations Concertantes pour Piano et Violon sur un Thême de la Cenerentola Musique de J. Rossini..par L. Schloesser. Oeuv. 3. Paris: Richault, n.d., Pl. no. 693; title page only (Box 16)
        - Walter, Georg Anton
          - Trois Duos pour deux Violons par Walter. Oeuvre 7me, Livre 1. Offenbach s/M: J. André, n.d., Pl. no. 868. (Box 16)
        - Wanhal, Johann Baptist
          - Sonata per il Piano-Forté con Violino obligato del Giovanni Wanhal. Lit:D. No. 1. Bonn: N. Simrock, n.d., Pl. no. 469. (Box 16)
      - Title only (Box 16)
        - [Printed fragments for piano and violin] No. 8. (Op. 53. No. 2.), Pl. no. 10474. (Box 16)
        - [Theme and variations for violin and piano] [E major], Pl. no. 693.R. (Box 16)
    - Strings - Manuscripts (Box 16, Box 57)
      - By Composer (Box 16, Box 57)
        - Beethoven, Ludwig van
          - Sonata in F., op. 17, viola and piano parts (Box 16)
        - Fairlamb, J. R.
          - Wedding March see: Mozart, Mass No. 12, Box 28
        - Hauf, F.
          - Sonata (Box 16)
        - Hummel, Johann Nepomuk
          - March Jubilato see: Mozart, Mass No. 12, Box 28
          - March Romain see: Mozart, Mass No. 12, Box 28
        - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix
          - On the Seashore (Box 16)
          - Sweet Souvenir (No. 1, Book 1) (Box 16)
        - Molinos of Milan
          - Tema and Variations (Box 16)
        - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
          - Die Entführung aus dem Seraglio. Overture., Violino primo and Violoncello parts (Box 57)
        - Nicolai, Philipp
          - Il Templario, excerpts (Box 16)
        - Raffelin, A.
          - Duetto en un solo violin (Box 16)
        - Ries, Ferdinand
          - Grand Sonata. Opus 21., piano and viola (Box 16)
        - Rubinstein, Anton
          - Sonata for piano and cello or viola, op. 18, violin part (Box 16)
        - Waldteufel, Emile
          - Always or Never Waltz (Box 16)
      - Title only (Box 16)
        - Budget of Blunders, violin - incidental music (Box 16)
        - Ladies Hornpipe, violin part; Includes: Highland Fling (Box 16)
        - Polonaise pour le Violon (Box 16)
        - [Polkas, Schottisches, Galops, Quadrilles], violino primo (Box 16)
        - [Compilation of solo violin parts] (Box 16)
        - [Miscellaneous polkas] (Box 16)
        - [Miscellaneous works - violin parts] (Box 16)
        - [Operatic overtures - violin parts] (Box 16)
    - Flute - Printed music (Box 17)
      - By Composer (Box 17)
        - Diabelli, Anton
          - Divertissements d'après des Themes de Rossini, Caraffa etc. pour Flute et Pianoforte composés par A. Diabelli. Liv. 1. Hambourg: A. Cranz, n.d. (Box 17)
        - Haydn, Franz Joseph
          - Sonate pour le Piano-Forte accompagnée d'une Flute obligée composée par J. Haydn. Oeuvre 102, Liv. I. Bonn: N. Simrock, n.d., Pl. no. 46. (Box 17)
        - Koehler, Henry
          - Air de Deux Petits Savoyards: Ascouta Jeannette [Dalayrac] varié pour la flute seule par Köhler. Berlin: Concha, n.d., Pl. no. 286. (Box 17)
          - Sonata concertante pour le Piano Forte et flute composée par Henry Koehler. Oeuvre 97. Bonn: N. Simrock, n.d., flauto obligato.; Pl. no. 1117 (Box 17)
        - Martin y Soler, Vicente
          - Una Cosa rara, Operette par Martin arrangée pour Deux Flutes Traversieres et Violoncelle par Ehrenfried. Majence: B. Schott, n.d., Pl. no. 162. (Box 17)
        - Nicholson, Charles
          - Nicholson's 12 Fants. F. & P. F. No. 5., Pl. no. 1431. (Box 17)
        - Ries, Ferdinand
          - La trente-troisième Sonate pour le Piano-Forté avec accompagnement de Flûte (ad libitum) par Ferd. Ries. Oeuvre 48. Bonn: N. Simrock, [1815?]., Pl. no. 1112. (Box 17)
        - Süssmayr, Franz Xaver
          - Der Spiegel von Arkadien, Opera, en Duos pour Deux Flutes Traversieres arrangées par Ehrenfried. No. 9. Maience: Schott, n.d., Pl. no. 204. (Box 17)
        - Winter, Peter
          - Ouverture aus des Opera Die Zauberflöte, das Labyrinth oder der Kampf mit den Elementen fur Clavecin oder Piano Forte mit Flöte von Herrn Capelmeister Winter. Berlin: J. J. Hummel, n.d., Pl. no. 1065. (Box 17)
      - Title only (Box 17)
        - Ecossaise für die Aura (et al.). Beilage zur allgemeinen musikal. Zeitung, No. 30; No. 5. (Box 17)
        - [Miscellaneous fragments], Pl. no. 762, 884 (Box 17)
    - Flute - Manuscripts (Box 17)
      - By Composer (Box 17)
        - Devienne, François
          - Six trios pour deux flutes (Box 17)
        - Gebauer, François René
          - Six duos pour deux flutes (Box 17)
        - Müller, Wenzel
          - [Unidentified], Duet for 2 flutes; flauto primo only (Box 17)
        - Spintler, Chr.
          - Varsovienne, Arranged for 2 flutes by A. Scherzer (Box 17)
      - Title only (Box 17)
        - [Collection of songs for solo flute (one with text) chromatic scale exercises on first page] (Box 17)
        - [Parts for flute and guitar music] (Box 17)
    - Harp - Printed music (Box 18)
      - Bochsa, (Robert) Nicolas Charles
        - Grand Duo pour Harpe et Piano avec Acc. d'Orchestre ad libitum par N. Ch. Bochsa. Paris: Schonenberger, n.d. (Box 18)
      - Labarre, Théodore
        - Duo pour harpe et piano sur des motifs de L'Eclair de F. Halevy composé par T. Labarre. Op. 86 Paris: Maurice Schlesinger, n.d., Pl. no. M.S.2482. (Box 18)
    - Harp - Manuscripts (Box 18)
      - Bochsa, N. Charles
        - Neuf Variations pour la harpe (Box 18)
    - Guitar (Box 18)
      - A collection of popular airs, student pieces for the guitar (Box 18)
    - Ensembles of 3 or more instruments - Printed music (Box 18-20)
      - Araciel, Diego de
        - Tre Terzetti per Serenata a Violino, Viola e Chitarra composti da Diego de Araciel. Offenbach sul Meno: J. André, n.d., Pl. no. 1118.; pasted over "Milano" (Box 18)
      - Beczwarzowsky, Antonin F.
        - III Sonates pour le Piano Forte avec Violon et Violoncelle obligés, par A. Beczwarzowsky. Oeuvre 3me. [Bonn]: N. Simrock, [1802?]., Pl. no. 238. (Box 18)
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van
        - [String Quartets], Op. 18, No. 1-3, Pl. no. 3973. (Box 18)
      - Cambini, Giuseppe Maria
        - Six Quatuors par Cambini. Op. 15., Pl. no. 63. (Box 18)
      - Clementi, Muzio
        - Tre sonate per il Clavicembalo o Forte Piano con l'accompagnamento d'un Violino e Basso composte dal Sig. Muzio Clementi. Opera 23. Vienna: Artaria Compl., n.d., Pl. no. 225. (Box 18)
      - Fesca, Friedrich Ernst
        - Quartetto. Op. 38, Pl. no. 2308. (Box 18)
      - Hoffmeister, Franz Anton
        - IV Trios Concertants pour Deux Violon et Basse Composés par M. Hoffmeister. Oeuvre 13m. Paris: Sieber Musicien, n.d. (Box 18)
      - Hummel, Johann Nepomuk
        - Six grandes symphonies de W. A. Mozart arrangées pour le Piano Forte avec accompagnement de Flûte, Violon et Violoncelle par J. N. Hummel. No. 5. Mayence: B. Schott, n.d., Pl. no. 2073. (Box 18)
      - Küffner, Joseph
        - Drey Quartetten für 2 Violinen, Bratsche & Violoncell, von Joseph Küffner. 48tes Werk. Offenbach a/M: Johann André, n.d., Pl. no. 3649.; Violin and viola parts are manuscript (Box 18)
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
        - No. 3 des cinq principaux Quintetti pour deux Violons, deux Violes & Violoncelle composés par W. A. Mozart. Offenbach s/M: Jean André, n.d., Pl. no. 1485 (Box 19)
      - Onslow, Georges
        - Trois Quatuors pour deux Violons, Alto et Basse par G. Onslow. Oeuv. 4, Liv. 1. Nouvelle Ed. Paris: I. Pleyel & Co., n.d., Pl. no. 4925. (Box 19)
      - Pieltain, P.
        - Six Quartettos for Two Violins, a Tenor and Violoncello composed by P. Pieltain. Op. 2. London: J. Cooper, [1785]., Signed by composer (Box 19)
      - Pleyel, Ignaz
        - Six Quatuors pour deux Violons, Alto & Violoncelle composés par I. Pleyel. Oeuvre 2d. Offenbach s/M: J. André, [1818]., Pl. no. 1392. (Box 19)
        - Trois sonates pour Clavecin ou Piano Forte avec Accompagnement d'une Flute ou Violon et Basse Composées par Pleyel. Livre I. Mayence: Schott, n.d., Pl. no. 103. (Box 19)
      - Rode, Pierre